Alexandros Filotheou

I hold a PhD in Robotics and I am qualified with a Master's degree in Control and Robotics. I have 7+ years of hands-on experience which includes SLAM, localisation, autonomous navigation, control, Computer Vision, and general integration and problem-solving. These I have acquired in real conditions with real robots as well as in simulation. I have mainly used ROS and ROS 2, but also MATLAB/Octave, all the while under Linux. My primary coding language is C++ and my secondary Python. I enjoy documenting my motivation and contributions in a clear and concise manner that acknowledges my audience's existing knowledge with regard to code, presentations, technical papers, or tutorials. Most of all I enjoy being a member of a team and solving problems.

Portfolio

Indicative publications: [1] [2] [3] — google scholar

 $Indicative \ software \ packages: \ \ \texttt{cbgl} \cdot \texttt{fsm-lo} \cdot \texttt{lama-odom} \cdot \texttt{pvhd} - \texttt{github}$

 $Demos / videos: cbgl \cdot fsm \cdot cultureid \cdot relief \cdot mpc$

Work Experience

2023.09 — present	Postdoctoral Research Associate Center for Research and Technology Hellas (CERTH), Thessaloniki, Greece
2018.09 - 2023.03	Research Engineer for NSRF projects Aristotle University of Thessaloniki, Greece
2016.09 - 2016.11	Teaching Assistant · DD2380 Artificial Intelligence KTH Royal Institute of Technology, Stockholm, Sweden
2011.10 - 2012.03 $2011.03 - 2011.05$ $2008.07 - 2009.06$	Database Designer · Egnatia Motorway S.A., Thessaloniki, Greece Application Developer (Int) · Egnatia Motorway S.A., Thessaloniki, Greece Telecommunications Engineer · OTE Group, Thessaloniki, Greece

Voluntary Experience

2013.10 – 2014.07 **Computer Vision Engineer**, PANDORA Robotics Team, Dept. of Electrical and Computer Engineering, Aristotle University of Thessaloniki

Education

2018.09 – 2023.06

2005.09 – 2013.07

Diploma

Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering
Aristotle University of Thessaloniki, Greece

2015.09 – 2017.06

Master of Science · Systems, Control, and Robotics
School of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science
KTH Royal Institute of Technology, Stockholm, Sweden

Computer and Other Skills

```
Languages C/C++, Python, shell, MATLAB/Octave, {PL/}SQL {Meta-}Operating Systems Linux, ROS 2, ROS
Tools git, OpenCV, Docker, Qt (cpp) | Tkinter (py), Behavior Trees, LATEX Control Techniques MPC
```

Languages

English Fluent — IELTS Score 8.5 (Greek Native)

References

Dr. Antonis Dimitriou · Coordinator of the projects for which I worked during my A.U.Th. years (+30) 697 88 96 350 | antodimi@auth.gr

Thessaloniki, Greece; July 2024 contact: (+30) 693 87 87 677 | alexandros.filotheou@gmail.com source: https://github.com/li9i/cv